wmplugins.com 2005-12-11

# wmplugins.com - Privacy Statement

_This document was last updated September 24, 2004._

Microsoft is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy statement explains data collection and use practices of the WMPlugins.com site only; it does not apply to other online or offline Microsoft sites, products or services. By accessing the Site, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this privacy statement.

## Collection of your Personal Information

When we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you, we will ask you for it. Generally, this information is requested when you are registering before entering a contest, ordering e-mail newsletters, joining a limited-access premium site, signing up for an event or training, or when purchasing and/or registering Microsoft products. Personal information collected by WMPlugins.com often is limited to e-mail address, language, country or location, but may include other information when needed to provide a service you requested.

When you buy and install a new product, we may ask you to register your purchase electronically. We keep this registration information on file with any information you've already given us on previous visits to our Web site.

WMPlugins.com also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of WMPlugins.com.

WMPlugins.com also collects information about which pages our customers visit within WMPlugins.com. This site visitation data is identified only by a unique ID number, and it is never linked with personal information unless a user consents as described below.

WMPlugins.com uses .NET Passport as its registration and authentication service. When you sign in to this site using .NET Passport, you will be asked to provide your e-mail address and a password to sign you in. This same Passport sign-in allows you to access many other Passport participating sites and services. To learn more about the Passport service, the information stored in the Passport profile, and how Passport uses and protects your personal information, please read the [.NET Passport privacy statement](http://www.passport.net/Consumer/PrivacyPolicy.asp?PPlcid=1033).

## Use of your Personal Information

The personal information collected on this Site will be used to operate the Site and to provide the service(s) or carry out the transaction(s) you have requested or authorized.

In support of these uses, Microsoft may use personal information to provide you with more effective customer service, to improve the Site and any related Microsoft products or services, and to make the Site easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the Site to your particular preference or interests. 

We may use your personal information to provide you with important information about the product or service that you are using, including critical updates and notifications. Additionally, with your permission, we may send you information about other Microsoft products and services, and/or share information with Microsoft partners so they may send you information about their products and services.

We may also use the information we collect to make the Site easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the Site to your particular preference or interests.

Microsoft occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as packaging, mailing and delivering prizes, answering customer questions about products and services, sending postal mail, and sending information about our products, special offers, and other new services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

Microsoft may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Microsoft or the Site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Microsoft and our family of Web sites; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Microsoft employees or agents, users of Microsoft products or services, or members of the public.

Personal information collected on the Site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Microsoft or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using the Site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. Microsoft abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. 

## Control of your Personal Information

Except as otherwise described in this statement, personal information you provide on the Site will not be shared outside of Microsoft and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your permission.

Please be aware that this privacy statement and any choices you make on the Site will not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to Microsoft in the context of other, separately operated, Microsoft products or services.

## Access to your Personal Information

You can review and edit the personal information and contact preferences you provided at this Site by updating your personal profile once you are logged into the site.

## Security of your Personal Information

Microsoft is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. Additionally, when we transmit sensitive personal information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

## Protection of Children's Personal Information

WMPlugins.com is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children.

## Use of Cookies

When someone visits the site, a cookie is placed on the customer's machine (if the customer accepts cookies) or is read if the customer has visited the site previously. One use of cookies is to assist in the collection of the site visitation statistics described above.

We also use cookies to collect information on which newsletter links are clicked by customers. This information is used to ensure we are sending information customers want to read. It is collected in aggregate form and never linked with your personal information.

Web beacons, also known as clear gif technology or action tags, may be used to assist in delivering the cookie on our site. This technology tells us how many visitors clicked on key elements (such as links or graphics) on a WMPlugins.com Web page. We do not use this technology to access your personally identifiable information on WMPlugins.com; it is a tool we use to compile aggregated statistics about WMPlugins.com Web site usage. We may share aggregated site statistics with partner companies but do not allow other companies to place clear gifs on our sites.

Microsoft also uses cookies in connection with the use of your .NET Passport account on the WMPlugins.com Web site, as explained in the [.NET Passport privacy statement](http://www.passport.net/Consumer/PrivacyPolicy.asp?PPlcid=1033).

If you choose to not have your browser accept cookies from the WMPlugins.com Web site, you will be able to view the text on the screens, however you will not experience a personalized visit nor will you be able to subscribe to the service offerings on the site.

Questions about cookies? [Read more](http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm).

## Links to Other Web Sites

The Site may contain links to other Web sites. Please be aware that this privacy statement applies solely to the information collected on the Site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web sites. We encourage you to be aware when you are leaving this Site and read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that you visit before providing any personal information.

## Changes to this Privacy Statement

We may occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this privacy statement, we will notify you either by placing a prominent notice on the home page of our web site or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates.

## Contact Information

Microsoft welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you believe that Microsoft has not adhered to this privacy statement, please contact us via this form or via postal mail at the address provided below, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

WMPlugins.com Privacy  
Microsoft Corporation  
One Microsoft Way  
Redmond, Washington 98052
